Mommy!
AT THE END OF THE TUNNEL
- What?
- I'm with Casimiro!
Lunch is ready!
I'm on the slide!
I like Mathematics.
You'll have to work hard.
If I do it wrong,
PH get a zero.
No, you won't get a zero.
Sweetie, time for bed.
Wait, let me tuck in Casimiro.
Come on, go to bed.
It's late, sweetheart.
Pick up, damn it!
Yes, I'm calling for Casimiro's
test results.
Joaquin.
No, my name is Joaquin.
Casimiro is my dog.
Yeah, he's very old.
He doesn't want to walk anymore.
Well, is there any type
of treatment
or operation that can be done?
But it wouldn't solve anything.
Okay, thank you.
I'm going to think about it.
HOW TO PUT A DOG TO SLEEP
WITHOUT PAIN
- Hi.
Did you put an ad
renting
a room with a terrace?
Can we see it?
Yes, but you should have called
before coming.
Come on, Betty.
It's up there.
- How cute! What's its name?
- Casimiro.
Don't touch him!
He doesn't like people
he doesn't know.
Do you live alone?
Yes.
I don't think this is what
you're looking for.
It's not the ideal place...
How do you know
what I'm looking for?
- Go up and look at it.
- Okay.
The door to the terrace
is next to the bathroom door.
Okay.
Can we move in today?
What?
My stuff is nearby,
I can bring it right over.
You'd be saving us
if you say yes.
- No, no...
- Here's what we'll do.
Don't say anything.
We'll be back in half an hour.
- Call me first.
- Don't show it to anyone.
Please, call me first.
- Half an hour.
- Thanks.
Thanks!
Come in, come in.
Thanks.
This one?
There.
Shouldn't it go over here?
Just asking.
I don't need company.
That's not why I rented the room,
to have someone organizing
and cleaning the house.
What bullshit.
What are these marks
on the door?
The marks...
When you're growing,
as you get taller...
How many lighters
do you use a day?
I'm only thinking of Betty...
Betty, the little girl
who's always with me.
Since you asked, I'll tell you.
I'm a dancer.
That's what I do.
I dance in a club.
I'm a stripper.
But not the kind you're thinking.
That wouldn't be my problem.
FORECLOSURE
FINAL NOTICE
Can you turn down the music
a little, please?
Excuse me.
Have you seen my daughter?
No.
- Could she have gone back there?
- No.
She couldn't have gone
back there.
Don't go back there.
She could have walked right by you
and you didn't see her.
Damn it. Betty!
Sweetie, are you out here?
Betty!
Are you here?
She likes to hide,
I don't know why.
She suddenly disappears.
That's locked, she couldn't have
gone in there.
- Did you check the bedroom?
- Yes, I did.
Betty!
Sweetheart!
Come here.
Hide in easier places to find!
Here, let me see your pockets.
I'll put this back where it goes.
Hey, how long has it been
since you saw the terrace?
You know what's out there?
Obviously not.
I can't describe it.
You have to come up and see it.
Yeah, I'd love to go skating too.
Come on.
In the contract
you made me sign...
I saw that today happens to be
your birthday.
You don't like kids?
You don't talk to her,
you barely look at her...
She doesn't talk to me
either.
She doesn't talk to anyone,
not even me.
She's not mute.
She just stopped talking.
The psychologist said it was better
not to pressure her.
Who do you spend
Christmas and New Year's with?
With Casimiro.
That's great.
There will be 4 of us now.
Were you always like this?
Like what?
Shall I take her to bed
and open another bottle?
Come on, sweetie.
Let's go.
I like to dance, but really dance.
You know?
I studied dance.
After that, I came to Buenos Aires,
and...
My old man's house
was full of books too.
There were books everywhere.
You don't care at all,
do you?
I'm listening.
If all you need is money,
why don't you sell this huge house?
This is my home.
Yeah, but this house
must be worth 600,000 dollars.
At least.
What a shitty birthday.
I wish I could dance, but...
Okay.
What are you doing?
It's what I do best.
Here?
Tomorrow we'll just say
it was the booze.
But no laughing
or teasing me about it.
No, Joaquin said not to!
Betty, that's enough!
I won't say it again!
Tell those two to stop
in there.
I heard something
at the cripple's place.
I didn't hear shit.
I said I heard something,
you dumbshit.
It was the elevator.
Lefty, should I take this?
Let me listen.
Keep quiet.
We should have plastered
on this wall.
I don't hear anything.
Tell those two come out.
Stay here and listen.
Let's all go back up.
What are you doing?
Come up here!
Don't miss this!
Your dog mummy woke up!
Don't be so insensitive!
- Come up here!
- I'm coming.
Come up!
He got up.
And he stood there
for a while.
Aren't you happy?
Yeah, can't you tell?
Is something wrong?
You look like shit.
No, I'm fine.
What is this?
This is that I'm not going
to let you keep working.
We'll cook and eat together
to celebrate Casimiro's revival.
I might not do a striptease
for you tonight...
I heard the cripple's elevator
10 minutes ago.
What do we do?
I checked, we're good.
Let's keep going.
Come on,
we need to hurry up.
How are things going in there,
Puppet?
- Hot but okay.
- Puppet?
PUPPET
- What am I, your servant?
- Why are you asking about the heat?
- Pichi, Pichi.
- What?
- Put that over there.
- Yes, sir, but...
We have to be more careful,
Papito.
Keep going,
quit screwing around.
One... second,
let me... turn on... the light.
How are we for 10 days?
Okay, I think.
SATURDAY DECEMBER 24TH
These beams are no good.
Take them upstairs,
they're in the way.
BEAMS?
Mr. Galereto,
should I take this up too?
No, leave it for now.
I'm going up to sleep
for a while.
I'll tell René to come down.
Canario, I'm taking this
to the table.
Whose glass is this?
Pass it over here.
Should we stop at 6?
Yeah, we'll see how it was.
You can't do this to me now.
We signed a contract,
you asked me a ton of questions.
We did sign a contract.
You don't trust me?
ls there a reason?
It has nothing to do with trust.
I just need a couple of weeks...
Why do we have to find
somewhere else right away?
I can't explain why, okay?
- Just give me a few days...
-l'll explain it.
You're scared because
we're getting closer.
Because the other night...
I danced for you.
That has nothing to do with it.
I saw how you look at me.
And you think less of yourself
because of that wheelchair.
You were comfortable
by yourself
and you're scared of losing that.
You're smart, Joaquin
and good-looking
but your life is awful and you
want to keep it that way.
I know you like me.
And you have no idea what I'm
going through and that scares you.
Think it over.
Tomorrow you can tell me
if you want us to leave.
But give it one more day,
please.
THEY WORK ONLY AT NIGHT
THEY CARRY DIRT UPSTAIRS IN BAGS
WHAT ARE THE BEAMS FOR?
Hi.
Good morning.
Want some coffee?
Yeah.
Thanks.
I'm going downstairs to work.
I thought it over.
And... I don't want you to leave.
That's it.
Come down when you can.
I want to show you something
you won't believe.
Schwarzenegger, Schwarzenegger,
when can we eat something?
You want to stop... and eat?
You're lazy even...
even with millions at stake.
This heat is unbearable.
Can't we do something?
Yeah, right. I'll install
some air conditioning later.
It's not silly, according to
our natal charts, it's better to do it
the 25th than the 24th.
I'm only asking for one more day.
Know what the horoscope said about
1/12th of the passengers on the Titanic?
"ldeal day for a trip."
We should do it on the 25th,
not the 24th.
- Trust me.
- Yeah, yeah.
Lefty, show me.
- I'm even trying to help...
- Look.
Will it be strong enough?
Yeah, I guess.
I don't know how it works in Spain,
but don't say I guess.
Don't worry, it'll be fine.
Did you set the detonator,
Canario?
Almost, almost.
But this is harder
than baptizing a cat.
"Almost, almost."
Galereto, you have a visitor.
- What is she doing here?
- Should we leave you alone?
What happened?
I came over the terrace.
Yeah, but what happened?
He changed his mind.
He said to move out.
- Did he go back down after 8'?
- No.
You're sure he can't hear
anything?
He can't hear anything, Javi.
From anywhere.
Keep stalling.
Tell him you'll look
and can't find anything.
Keep him occupied.
Look what I got you.
- Besides the crap you buy me...
- Crap?
Stop groping me.
You don't give a shit
what happens to me.
You leave me with another guy
-and you don't give a fuck.
- He's a cripple.
Or I wouldn't have gotten you into this.
You know Pm crazy about you.
- I wish I believed you.
- What's wrong, baby?
Of course I am.
You're making me horny.
Go on, I have to keep working.
Listen.
No matter what happens,
don't come back here.
It was dangerous.
Message, nothing else.
I'm serious, baby.
Can I come down?
What?
I'll be right up.
You weren't going to show me
something?
Is something wrong?
Yeah, I wanted to show you...
something on YouTube.
ls your daughter up there?
- Yeah.
- Okay, I'll be right up.
Okay.
Sweetie, those felt pens
stain everything.
Look at your hands.
Okay, let's see.
Cream cheese, sweet potato jelly,
toothpaste, wine, soap,
rice, cookies, mayonnaise.
Anything else?
Nothing else.
Don't worry, she won't go anywhere.
I think.
Bye, sweetie!
What you're drawing
is very pretty.
It's beautiful, what is it?
Very pretty.
That's a nice color.
You don't want to tell me
what it is?
Tell me when you finish it.
Bye, Casimiro.
- These pipes move a lot.
- They need a brace.
Maybe we should find something
bigger.
Then we can get more
out of each trip.
Yeah.
Look what I found
in Puppet's things.
Where was it?
In the pocket of his backpack.
He sent the last message
at 11 P.M.
He's asleep now.
Get Puppet over here.
Lefty, where did you find
this guy?
You know where. Why?
He sent the address
of the bank.
Why?
Why the fuck did you hit me?
What is this?
Tell me, I'm listening.
What is this doing here?
I didn't realize.
You didn't realize what?
The cell phone.
I forgot that I had it.
Lay on the table.
No, why?
Lefty, pal, explain it to him.
Lower your voice
and lay on the table.
I'm sorry, sir, I didn't mean to...
You'd better do as I say.
I put it in my bag before...
Stop talking. I'll listen to you
when you lay on the table.
Don't tie me up, guys.
There's no need.
I forgot I had it...
It's okay, we'll let you talk.
It's okay.
We're going to tie you up,
it's not up to you.
I put it in my bag
and I forgot...
I forgot, that's all...
Don't tie me up, guys.
There's no need.
You know what?
Let me talk.
You can talk after.
I asked you, like the others,
if you could disappear.
Yeah, I can, I can...
I also checked to make sure
it was true.
And also we agreed
that anyone who wanted to make
a call or send a message
would do it in front of me, right?
Yes, sir. You're right.
I didn't mean to...
Lower your voice
or I'll have to put a bullet
in your head.
I swear.
I swear...
- I didn't know...
- Open your mouth.
No... No...
I'm going to put this rag
in your mouth.
- No...
- This is going to hurt.
You'll scream. I'm going to stab you
in the leg with this screwdriver.
I'll tell you anything.
Anything.
Who did you send the message to
with the bank address?
A girl named Jessica.
I like her.
I met her before we started.
Why did you send her that?
She was angry because
I hadn't written her.
I thought I could see her
when I went to do
the shopping.
- That's the truth.
-ls it?
That's what her messages said.
It's true!
I'm telling the truth!
What a fucking stupid reason
to die.
Don't kill me.
I don't want to see her.
Now you can't be here
anymore.
Because now the girl knows
you didn't leave town.
He told her he was working
near the bank.
See what I mean?
When she hears about
the robbery,
she may be dumb,
but she'll connect you to this.
What if she knows you've done
other jobs before?
She doesn't know, I swear.
How do I know
if she knows or not?
She must know someone
who knows you
from the neighborhood
or strip club where you met her.
You know why this is happening?
Because you didn't tell her
you were out of town.
What's wrong, you idiot?
You think I'm sadistic?
Shut your mouth!
Keep quiet or I'll really kill you.
You got that?
If you're a cop...
and the messages were code,
tell me right now.
Because Guttman is in on this.
You know who he is?
No...
I don't know who he is.
If you're a cop, he's the only one
that can save you.
I'm not a cop...
I just want to keep working...
I want to work!
Let me think it over.
Just shut up and hold still.
That's the best thing
you can do.
Let me go...
Keep the cell phone.
We have to keep texting the girl.
What do we do with him?
Guttman can help us out.
Get some plastic and tape.
Afraid?
I don't know, of normal things,
I guess.
Taxi drivers, police,
talk shows...
Like anybody else.
My turn, right?
Well...
Will you ever walk again?
I'd like to.
Maybe with an operation.
Really?
Why don't you do it?
No, let's not talk about this.
Something else.
Okay, fine.
- Yeah.
- Let's see.
Ever been in love?
Yeah.
Once.
My turn. You?
Oh, many times.
It's so easy
to find someone
who doesn't just want to fuck you...
Especially with a daughter...
There are plenty of nice,
sweet guys out there...
What does that mean?
It means exactly what I said.
I'll ask you another way.
Are you seeing anyone?
Why?
Are you going to make
an indecent proposal?
No, I just want to see
if you're telling me the truth.
Tell me something.
When was the last time
someone fell in love with you?
I stopped thinking about that.
Don't be ridiculous.
Any girl could fall for you,
with or without
a wheelchair.
Go ahead,
laugh. You think women
are like men. That we only...
What's wrong?
What are you feeling?
I don't know,
like I just smoked 8 joints.
I don't know.
I don't know what's wrong with me.
Lie down in my bedroom.
I think I can make it upstairs.
No, you're not going to make it.
Lie down here, it's okay.
Oh, no...
I don't know
what happened to me.
I feel so out of it.
What are you doing?
Stop!
This is for the dizziness.
- It will help you sleep.
- But...
You can fuck me
without doing this.
I'm not going to fuck you.
I don't understand
why you're doing this.
Because I know everything.
I know what you're doing.
They'll kill you.
You're going to sleep
for a while.
What about Betty...?
She has nothing to do with this.
Nothing...
Betty will be fine.
Careful.
Are we ready? Just turn.
Try it.
- Are we on schedule?
- I think so.
Take note.
Boxes 747 and 748 are
connected to the alarm,
-but we can't touch them.
- Why?
Guttman warned me.
They're full of cash
but it's narco money.
If we touch it we're dead.
Fuck, what if the narcos
have more money in there?
Guttman is a schmuck
but he isn't fucking stupid.
Write it down:
do not touch 747 and 748.
Look, Galereto.
This is what will explode.
Are you sure?
I'll have to attach it
to the roof of the tunnel.
It should stay there
a few hours before detonating.
Okay, we'll prepare it
the night before we go in.
Listen, we detonate it
and a chunk of the vault
will collapse.
- We can climb up.
- Excuse me, Princess.
The schmuck calls me Princess.
- You'll have to go in.
- Me?
- What?
- You have to replace Puppet.
Damn it!
Can't somebody else go?
- Listen.
- Spare me your astrology bullshit.
I don't know what you're trying to do,
but it won't work.
What do you see in him?
He would never hurt anyone.
He's not a bad person.
He's been good to me
and Betty.
He's a good father for Betty?
That's what you want?
Or in Corrientes, where you were born.
She doesn't know anything, I swear.
She must know someone
who knows you
from the neighborhood
or strip club where you met her.
You know why this is happening?
Because you didn't tell her
you were out of town.
What's wrong, you idiot?
You think I'm sadistic?
ls it good?
Your mom isn't feeling well.
You can see her
when she wakes up.
Know what I was thinking,
Betty?
I'd like you to bring down
your things from upstairs
and you can sleep
in a room down here,
that one over there.
The one that's locked.
It's a beautiful room.
I didn't do anything.
I didn't do anything...
So bring your clothes down,
okay?
You can take Casimiro with you.
Is that okay?
Don't be afraid, Betty.
Don't be afraid of me.
I promise I'll never hurt you.
Ever.
I'll never do anything bad to you.
We need to find Casimiro a...
a blanket or something.
Come on.
You can play with anything
in here.
Anything you want.
How long has it been
since Betty last spoke?
When she was 4 years old.
And one day she just stopped talking.
Nothing I told you was a lie.
Nothing.
I believed everything you told me.
What are you going to do?
Maybe I can help you avoid
them killing you.
They won't kill me.
Be careful when you send
text messages from my phone.
You have to put
a space before the first word.
Repeat some letters
-and always end with a period.
- You think
I can't beat him?
I already noticed.
He's going to realize.
I'm going to steal
part of what they take.
Are you crazy?
Three will be in the bank,
three waiting for the money.
Joaquin, you can't do that.
You haven't seen what
they're capable of.
There's no way they'll notice.
Sell this house if you need money.
Why do that?
Son of a bitch!
What's wrong?
There's a pipe
that shouldn't be there.
- A pipe?
- Yeah, a large water pipe.
There can't be a pipe there.
The pipe is right in the middle.
Right in the middle.
Did we turn too soon?
This has to be the pipe,
it's the only one.
Then we must have done this.
They turned 2 meters too soon.
How did you fuck this up?
- Spaniards don't know the metric system?
- Shut up!
We barely touched it.
How much time have we lost?
BUENOS AIRES WATER PIPES
We won't make it
to the day after tomorrow?
We have to correct several meters
and prepare the roof for the charge.
Forget about Saturday.
We wait until Sunday
and go in earlier.
- What's wrong?
- This is much better.
Yeah, Mars and Saturn were out of line.
Working 4 more hours a day we can make it up.
- Seriously?
- We have no choice.
Start correcting.
Look at this.
Am I a genius or what?
What the fuck are you talking about?
Instead of the shitty carts,
we'll use this.
We can fit more.
Less trips, less time.
If it tips over, nothing falls out.
Put wheels on it
and we'll try it out.
That's why I'm saying
we need to be careful.
I know that. You think I'm not
careful enough?
Pass me the tape measure.
We need light.
Come on, bonehead.
You'll get covered in dirt.
Here, put it on the table.
I don't want it to get dirty.
The lights are on.
What dumbshits.
Look, these are burned out.
Leaving them on all day
with the heat down here.
- Come on, go faster.
- Wait, wait...
It looks okay.
It's what they said.
- Did you measure right?
- Yeah.
Lefty's taking everything
to the house in Lomas.
That place is perfect.
You mean he knows about
the house in Lomas?
Him, you and me.
Nobody else.
You might as well put our hideout
in the newspaper.
Did something happen between
you and Lefty?
No, nothing.
You're the boss here.
But did something happen?
I just think you're trusting people
too much who you hardly know.
Don't bust my balls, Pedro.
Lefty's a good guy.
If you know something I don't,
tell me.
Lefty's a good guy.
He won't give us any trouble.
He's great at what he does.
Yeah, he's the one
who brought Puppet.
Stop busting my balls.
You always get like this
with somebody new.
You're my brother, I trust you.
What do you mean, you jerk?
That I'm jealous? Why ask me
if you know him better than me.
Why the hell are you asking me?
This is great, a fucking Spaniard,
a stutterer, a lesbian
and a puppet.
What a melting pot.
Betty.
Betty...
Betty!
Betty... Betty!
It's an illusion they created
to dominate, so people
won't bother them.
I know, I know.
It's true, you're right.
And they call it "ethics."
Like I read once:
"What's robbing a bank
compared to founding one?"
Where is Guttman?
Falling a day behind
is not good.
It's not good.
Of course it's not good, Guttman.
But sometimes unexpected things
happen.
We're done with the curve.
Tonight we'll be under
the safety deposit boxes.
Then we go in the day
after tomorrow?
The tunnel will end
10 centimeters under the vault
for a small explosive.
We detonate and go in.
It's faster and we won't need
so many tools.
We'll go in at 8.
But then the partying won't cover
the noise?
On the 25th people light
firecrackers all day too.
- Lefty, what's wrong?
- What?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
I can't find my watch.
I left it here and it's gone.
If you need to interrupt
for any other
important reason,
go ahead.
The explosion
won't be too big, right?
We used it on another job.
Nobody will hear it.
Let's go.
It's going to rain on Sunday.
That's good for us.
Monday is when they'll realize.
After that,
it's your problem, Guttman.
Yeah, and you guys
will be far away by then.
What's wrong, Canario?
The tarp looked funny to me.
I need to talk to you.
Look.
These are the safety deposit boxes
you can't touch
because they're connected
to the alarm.
- Got it?
- Got it.
Is it true you're retiring
after this job?
That's right.
That's what they all say.
There's a girl.
I'm leaving with her.
Money and the girl I love,
all at once.
Write down this number:
155.
155? ls that the one?
Yeah.
You'll find an envelope,
loose papers,
it doesn't matter.
Anything in there
is what I'm after.
You're not going to tell me
what it is?
Trust me, you don't want to know.
If you're smart,
you won't look either.
Guttman, I don't give a shit
what they're extorting you with.
Photos banging your mother
or a 3-month-old baby
or a government minister,
I don't care.
Everything will be down
on Sunday.
I can send the patrols
somewhere else.
But only until 11,
after that I can't.
Stay calm and don't make
a mess.
Here, give me your hand.
Come on.
It's over, it's over.
Are you okay?
It's over. It's over.
What's this?
What did you do?
Stop, stop, stop.
Please.
Stop.
Let me go, please...
He's calling you.
I need you to answer it.
Please, I'm asking you.
- Help me.
- Why should I help you?
Because I'm asking you to,
damn it!
Let me go.
You know Betty talks?
She talks to Casimiro.
I put a microphone
on his collar. Listen.
Come on, Casimiro.
Pm not going to hurt you.
Are you hungry?
Come here, I'll give you a kiss.
No, please.
Let me keep listening.
Please.
You said she was 4
when she stopped talking.
Yes.
How old is she now, 6?
Two years?
When did this guy
come into your life?
When did you meet Galereto?
More or less the same.
A little over two years.
A little over two years?
Mommy's boyfriend
wants you to do these things.
We're going to play a game.
But we can't tell Mommy.
Mommy will be jealous
if we tell her.
Boys and girls always play
like this.
Come here, little one.
Don't be afraid, Casimiro.
No, no!
It's okay.
No,no,no!
No, please!
She's okay now, she's okay.
She's playing with some toys
I gave her.
That son of a bitch!
Now that we know,
we can help her.
I'll ruin his life, I swear.
I don't care about that.
I can screw him over.
I'm going to flood the tunnel.
I'll ruin his whole plan.
I can ruin his life.
I'm going to kill him!
Calm down.
I need you to calm down.
Think about what's happening.
And help me.
What do you want me to do?
Call him, talk to him.
Tell him everything is fine.
That everything is fine.
Not to worry.
Tell him everything's fine.
He's calling you.
Talk to him.
Hi.
- How are you?
- Fine. What's happend?
Yeah, I'm whispering
because he's nearby.
- Everything is okay?
- I can't talk long.
Don't worry, he hasn't gone
to the basement.
Yeah, I miss you too.
Not my baby...
Son of a bitch!
Son of a bitch...
No, no!
Don't shoot me up anymore!
Please! Let me see her!
I need to see her!
Please, trust me.
- Please.
- Trust me.
Everything will be okay.
What, you still think your watch
is going to show up?
I left it here.
We're all decent people here.
It could be in the bags of dirt.
Finally after 500 years a Spaniard
finally brings something to this land.
What's your fucking problem,
Canario?
Everything I do bothers you.
Everything okay?
ls it still intact?
Yeah. It hasn't moved.
- Did you check the charge?
- Yeah.
Don't worry. A piece of the floor
will fall, not the whole bank.
Okay...
We did a good job.
Clear your minds,
don't say anything.
- Can we get some rest?
- Yeah.
We go in at 8.
I'm going to lock the door, okay?
I'll be right back.
Do you need to check it?
No.
And René?
What do we do?
- Everything's ready.
- Then let's do it.
- It's stupid to wait.
- Let's go.
We should wait until the right time.
No, no, no.
We blow it and go in now.
Okay.
Pass me the detonator.
Turn on the ventilator.
- Where's the wire?
- Come on.
- Get out of there.
- Let's go.
Watch your head.
- Get out of there.
- Come on, you idiot.
Come on, here we go!
Let's go.
Here we go!
- Go on.
- Wait.
Careful, you'll hit your head.
Tell me if everything's okay.
Go ahead.
Pass me that rope.
Here.
Come on.
Come here.
Listen.
It sounds like water.
There's water down there?
René, can you hear me?
ls there water down there?
We need to get out!
Bring everything!
We have to get out!
What are you doing?
We're not going to make it.
Canario!
I can't make it, Canario!
I can't see her!
Don't go down there,
it could collapse.
We need to get out of here!
Come on!
Canario!
Canario, you bastard!
Help me! Help me!
Help me, you bastard!
There's a guy down here!
Son of a bitch!
I've got him!
Help me, you bastard!
There's a guy down here!
He's down here!
Open up! Open UP!
Open up, you son of a bitch!
Open Up, Open up!
Help me!
Open up!
We have to sound the alarm.
Berta.
Berta, can you hear me?
It didn't go right.
I killed someone, Berta.
Where's my daughter?
I just saw her, she's fine.
The money's there.
In the closet, in the backpack.
I don't give a shit about the money.
Tell me what happened.
They left.
You idiot!
They'll come back! And what do you
think will happen to me?
I couldn't trust you.
Yes, you could.
You know you could.
Now you're on your own.
I didn't risk you two.
I didn't...
You don't know what it means.
I have to take care of her, Joaquin.
I have to go.
Let me go.
I have to take care of my daughter.
I can take care of you both.
We can leave, the three of us.
Together.
I'm sorry.
I really like you.
But I can't.
Here!
We're trapped in the vault!
Excuse me. Excuse me!
Over here, over here.
Excuse me, sir.
You can't be here.
I live over there.
My basement is flooded.
They cut the water and they're
going to pump it out.
Go back to your home.
You can't be here.
Okay, thanks.
- Hello.
- What happened?
I have no fucking idea
what happened.
Water started coming
from everywhere.
Calm down.
Calm down? I have three people
in the vault!
Where are you?
Did you get my things?
There wasn't time.
Everything flooded...
Hello? Hello?
Who is it?
Police!
Good evening, sir.
Officer Cristiani.
- Are you alone at home?
- No.
My wife and daughter
are here.
Would you mind if we came inside?
Please, I was waiting
for someone to come.
My whole basement is flooded.
All my work stuff.
I went outside and they said
to wait here.
Apparently a pipe burst
under the bank.
And who's going to pay for
my stuff down there? The bank?
Where are your wife
and daughter?
They're asleep. With this mess,
I didn't want to wake them up.
Please tell them not to worry.
We have to search the house.
You have to search my house
because of a broken pipe?
It looks like someone
tried to rob the bank.
Please, let's not waste
any more time.
- Okay.
- Go with him.
They're here to see why
it's flooded. It's okay.
I'll leave the flashlight there.
If it was a robbery,
will the bank pay for the damage?
This is only the beginning.
You'll have to be patient.
No.
No, no, thanks.
No, no, really.
I have to go.
Come and shut the door.
Give me your cell phone.
That one right there.
Here.
Now you have my number.
If you find anything strange
or you remember anything,
call me.
Okay.
Another team will come tomorrow
to take a closer look.
Leave everything where it is,
don't touch anything.
I definitely don't want
to go down there.
The lights should be back on
-in a few hours.
- Thank you.
Chief.
Who is it?
Police, sir.
Do you mind if we come inside?
The police were just here.
They already searched the house.
Another brigade.
It will only be a minute.
Okay.
Sure, come in.
That's the basement.
- Yeah.
- They stole the narcos box, you idiot!
BOX 748.
You're dead if you don't
give back that money.
I know these guys,
I can send them over if you want.
What you're saying
is impossible.
I can't talk to you right now.
Give me time, I'll check it out.
L know you think I'll kill you
so they can't connect you to me.
I can't talk right now,
I'll call you back.
You son of a bitch.
Tell me where you are!
What's wrong?
- Nothing, go to sleep.
- You haven't eaten?
Eat something sweet
or your sugar will be too low.
Tell me.
What happened down there?
Water started coming
from everywhere.
It looks like the floor
caved in
because they were making
a tunnel
to rob the bank next door.
At least that's what
the other policemen said.
Does anyone else live here?
No.
No, not anymore.
Until yesterday there was a girl
with her daughter,
they were renting a room
upstairs with a terrace.
But they left.
They left?
Yeah.
They were...
They were looking for an apartment.
She said they found one.
So...
- Did they leave an address?
- No.
No,
they didn't.
They said they'd be back
for their stuff.
So if you need anything...
Right.
If I ask you for permission
to search the house,
would that be okay?
You're already searching
the basement.
I just want to make sure
that everything's okay.
The police
already searched every room
in the house.
Look...
I think you're right,
there's no need.
So the girl and her daughter
are gone?
No, no.
Let's go.
Berta.
Can you hear me?
What did you do to her?
Nothing. I didn't do anything.
What's wrong with her?
I think you and I need to talk.
Well?
It looks like the water
made the floor cave in.
I don't understand what's
happening, officer.
Can I call you officer?
Why did you say they had left?
She told me to say
that they had left.
And why is she drugged
with marks from being tied up?
Marks from being tied up?
Who would have tied her up?
- I have no idea.
- That's why I'm asking.
I don't know.
Why is she in your bed?
She wasn't feeling well.
She took a pill, felt dizzy,
so I said use my bed.
She couldn't make it upstairs.
You know this makes no sense.
But I'm telling you the truth.
Is the paralysis true
or is that a lie too?
It's not a lie.
None of it is a lie.
When someone tells a lie,
they have to tell at least
two more to cover it up.
And then four more
to cover those two.
You reach a point where
you don't even know how it started.
Listen to me.
Please...
Listen.
You'd better tell me everything
that happened here.
I swear I have no idea.
I have no idea, I swear.
- Did you see her talk to anyone?
- No.
It's important for you
to understand something.
You saw our faces.
We have to kill you.
I don't know who you are.
Right now we are death
personified for you.
I don't understand.
You only have two options.
You're in a narrow corridor
with two doors.
The first door is the one
you've chosen so far:
Play dumb and stall
to see if that saves you.
But that door leads to
the worst death
you can imagine.
Extremely painful.
You'll watch us hurt you,
chop you to pieces,
break your bones,
take out your teeth,
all very slowly,
with blood everywhere.
It will surprise you.
How much your body
can take before you die.
The second door
is the smart one.
You talk, tell me
everything you know,
and you die quickly,
without even realizing.
It's up to you.
Which door will you choose?
Put the rag on him.
No, no...
So you won't scream.
Because you're going to,
it's impossible not to.
Are you sure
you don't want to talk?
Hello?
I'm outside your front door.
Come on in, motherfucker.
- Help me understand this.
- What's going on?
What are you doing here?
Are you crazy?
- Give me back my gun!
- You've got some explaining to do.
- What are you doing?
- Walk.
Walk, walk.
Walk.
Explain. Why did you call
that cell phone?
You explain to me.
I have people on the way.
Explain everything to me!
Listen closely.
Where the hell did you get
that cell number?
That guy sent me a message
saying to come.
Tie him up.
No, I'll stay put.
You don't have to tie me up.
Listen to me.
In 5 minutes there will be
cops everywhere.
Yeah, right. And you come
to ring the doorbell first.
You think I'm fucking stupid?
Listen to me!
I don't understand this either!
Don't worry, we're going
to figure it out.
Look!
Listen to me, you bastard.
I don't understand shit here.
Explain this to me.
Why did he call you?
I don't know, I swear.
Bring Berta out here,
she's in his room.
They have two minutes to talk
or we're gone.
Put her in his wheelchair.
Guttman!
Watch. In one minute
you're next.
No,no,no!
Don't kill him!
You'll complicate everything!
Stop, stop!
Lefty! Lefty! Please!
Don't let him kill me, Lefty!
Tell him!
How does he know your name?
How should I know?
Talk!
Tell him or I will.
Tell him.
Please.
Talk, motherfucker!
How the hell do you know him?
Please, Lefty. Tell him.
I have no fucking idea
what he's talking about.
I don't know him.
You have 3 seconds
before I blow your head off.
In the evening...
he'd sneak up to the terrace.
To see Berta.
What?
He told me about the robbery.
He's making this up!
Let him talk!
He and Berta told me
about the robbery.
About the tunnel.
He said to make a hole
in my basement
to grab the money
from the carts.
We were going to split it
three ways.
But then you changed
to cat carriers.
Son of a bitch!
I told you he was a son of a bitch!
He's making it all up, I swear!
I'm making it up?
He tied up Berta.
He beat her, I don't know why.
He wanted to keep her asleep.
He gave me injections
to keep her drugged.
He didn't trust her
and he was afraid she'd talk.
You're doing her, is that it?
Galereto?
You're Galereto,
right?
And you're Canario, right?
You three are going to hide
in a house in Lomas?
Nobody else knew about that.
I have no fucking idea
how he knows that.
Shut the fuck up
and let him talk!
Look, there's a key in that drawer.
Open the door.
You'll see I'm not lying.
He left it here.
Pedro, no!
No,no,no!
Pedro, it's okay.
It's okay, bro.
Don't go...
Son of a bitch!
Son of a bitch...
Fucking bitch!
Sweetheart...
I'm sorry, baby. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry...
That's it, it's over.
That's it.
You need to go.
Please, get her out of here.
She needs to get out of here.
Stay where you are!
In the end...
no matter how organized
your plan is,
it always depends on
either a girl or luck.
Stop aiming that at me.
What are you going to do,
bury 4 bodies in the basement?
So you stole his girlfriend.
Of course, that's my job,
you know.
To know everything.
Scrub the stains
with oxygenated water.
That's the only thing
that gets the blood out.
Okay.
Where's the money you took?
I take half the money,
and you think about all the things
I won't do to screw up your life.
I can screw up your life too.
These are the safety deposit boxes
you can't touch
because they're connected
to the alarm.
It's true that after...
What you've got there only saves you
for the time being.
The time being, that's all.
Pick which one goes first.
The backpack with the money
is right there.
Erase what you've got there,
trust me.
Believe me, you can't afford it.
In the end...
Like I said before.
Everything depends on a girl
or luck.